Register of the Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration photograph negatives
Hoover Institution Archives
Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration photograph negatives
1946-1947
48024
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes (2.9 linear feet)
Depicts scenes of daily life in China and activities of the Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.
Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1948.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Archival Materials note
Larry Gahn photographs, Hoover Institution Archives
Historical Note
The Chinese Nationalist Government created the Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (CNRRA) in January 1945. CNRRA was a temporary organization charged with administering and coordinating the China-based operations of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), which had been established at a 44-nation conference in 1943 to carry out global reconstruction in the wake of the Second World War. Dr. T. F. Tsiang, CNRRA's Director-General, and T. V. Soong, who chaired the Special Cabinet Committee on Relief and Rehabilitation, oversaw the organization. Its functions included administering emergency relief, returning refugees to their homes, rehabilitating China's agricultural and industrial sectors and establishing a public health program. Initially, CNRRA was headquartered in Chongqing (Chunking), China's wartime capital. In December 1945, however, it relocated its operations center to Shanghai and created a headquarters in Nanjing (Nanking). The agency distributed UNRRA supplies through free relief and direct sales at regional offices in Guangzhou (Canton), Changsha, Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), Hangzhou (Hangchow), Wuhan (Hankow), Kaifeng, Guilin (Kweilin), Shenyang (Mukden), Nanchang, Shanghai, Taipei, Taiyuan, Tianjin (Tientsin), Qingdao (Tsingtao), Wuhu.
CNRRA's efforts were hampered by the breakdown in interparty peace negotiations between the Nationalists and Chinese Communists in 1946. China's northern provinces, which had been under a long occupation by the Japanese, were also areas of Chinese Communist guerilla activity. After the Japanese surrender these territories fell under Chinese Communist control. Difficulties arose in the distribution of aid due to the realities of civil war. The official history of the CNRRA estimates that 2-3 percent (by weight) or 4-5 percent (by value) of all UNRRA supplies were distributed to Communist-held territories.
CNRRA was disbanded in 1948, after the mandate of UNRRA expired in 1947. UNRRA's programs were assumed by agencies within the new United Nations, particularly the Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) and the World Health Organization (WHO), and the International Refugee Organization (IRO).
Sources: UNRRA: The History of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, George Woodbridge (NY: Columbia University Press, 1950) 3 vol.; "UNRRA: A Case Study in Financial Assistance for Economic Development," Irving Barnett, Ph.D. thesis, Columbia University, 1955; UNRRA Microfilms, 1943-1949, Joshua Lupkin, finding aid, published in electronic form, January 2003, available from the World Wide Web: (http://www.columbia.edu/cu/libra ries/indiv/rare/guides/UNRRA/index.html); and CNRRA: Its Purpose, Functions and Organization (Shanghai: Department of Public Relations, CNRRA, 1946).
Scope and Content Note
The collection depicts scenes of daily life in China and the activities of the CNRRA between 1945 and 1947. It consists of four manuscript boxes (boxes 1-4) containing 2,179 4 x 5 inch and 2.5 x 2.5 inch safety negatives, and 33-mm nitrate negatives; and three boxes (boxes 5-7) holding the original paper sleeves in which the negatives were housed.
The Hoover Institution acquired these photographic negatives, and other records of UNRRA's China office, from the Shanghai office prior to its closing. Most of the CNRRA's records, measuring 8,500 linear feet, are located in the United Nations Archives in New York City.
CNRRA used the U.S. Postal Service Geographic Names to romanize Chinese place names. The following container list reflects both the original romanization, placed in parentheses, as well as the current conventional romanization of Chinese place names established by the United States Board on Geographic Names and the Getty Thesaurus of Geographic Names.
Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China--Pictorial works.; International relief.; China--Pictorial works.
- Photographic Negatives, 1946-1947 (Boxes 1-4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged numerically by negative number, 0001-2229, with gaps.
  - Jiangwan (Kiangwan) Airfield, photographer Warren Lee (0001-0002), undated (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0003-0004), 1946 April 22 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0005-0009), 1946 May 7 (Box 1)
  - CHT Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0010-0012), 1946 April 19 (Box 1)
  - Markham Road, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0013-0023), 1946 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0024-0026), 1946 May 14 (Box 1)
  - Wusong (Woosung), Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0027-0029), 1946 May 10 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0030-0032), 1946 May 16 (Box 1)
  - Yangtzepoo, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0033-0039), 1946 May 16 (Box 1)
  - Zikawei, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0040-0043), 1946 May 23 (Box 1)
  - Ward Road, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0044-0045), 1946 May 22 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0046), 1946 May 22 (Box 1)
  - Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), photographer Warren Lee (0047-0058), 1946 May 25 (Box 1)
  - Changzhou (Changchow), photographer Warren Lee (0059-0060), 1946 May 24 (Box 1)
  - Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), photographer Warren Lee (0061-0068), 1946 May 26 (Box 1)
  - Park Hotel, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0069), 1946 May 2 (Box 1)
  - Changzhou (Changchow), photographer Warren Lee (0070-0071), 1946 May 24 (Box 1)
  - Saint John's College, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0072-0074), 1946 June 3 (Box 1)
  - Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), photographer Warren Lee (0075-0080), 1946 June 4 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0081-0087), 1946 June 7 (Box 1)
  - Pudong (Pootung), photographer Warren Lee (0088-0094), 1946 June 12 (Box 1)
  - Xuzhou (Hsuchow), photographer Warren Lee (0095-0108), 1946 June 16 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0109-0110), 1946 June 28 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0111), 1946 June 28 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0112-0120), 1946 June 29 (Box 1)
  - Point Island, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0121-0127), 1946 July 4 (Box 1)
  - Chongqing (Chunking), photographer Warren Lee (0128-0133), 1946 January (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0134-0135), 1946 July 15 (Box 1)
  - Longhua (Lunghwa) Airfield, photographer Warren Lee (0136-0140), 1946 July 16 (Box 1)
  - Beijing (Peiping), photographer Larry Gahn (0141-0172, 0148 and 0159 are missing), 1946 July (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0173), 1946 June (Box 1)
  - Beijing (Peiping), photographer Larry Gahn (0174), 1946 July (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0175-0176), 1946 July 17 (Box 1)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Dick Wilson (0177-0184), 1946 June 24 (Box 1)
  - Tungkon Guangdong (Kwangtung), photographer Dick Wilson (0185), 1946 June 16 (Box 1)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Dick Wilson (0186-0192), 1946 June 25 (Box 1)
  - Kunong, photographer Dick Wilson (0193-0195), 1946 July 7 (Box 1)
  - Liangkou, photographer Dick Wilson (0196-0198), 1946 July 4 (Box 1)
  - Ling Ling, photographer Dick Wilson (0199-0200), 1946 July 4 (Box 1)
  - Tianjin (Tientsin), photographer Larry Gahn (0201-0223, 0207 and 0217 are missing), 1946 July (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0224-0239), 1946 July 27 (Box 1)
  - Yangtzepoo, photographer Warren Lee (0240-0249), 1946 July 29 (Box 1)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Dick Wilson (0250-0255), 1946 June 20 (Box 1)
  - Kowloon, photographer Dick Wilson (0256-0258), 1946 June 14 (Box 1)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Dick Wilson (0259-0261), 1946 June 21 (Box 1)
  - Zhengzhu (Jengju), Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0262-0274), 1946 July 30 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0275-0276), 1946 July 30 (Box 1)
  - Zhengzhu (Jengju), Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0277-0278), 1946 July 30 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0279-0284), 1946 July 30 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai Wharf, photographer Warren Lee (0285-0291), 1946 August 1 (Box 1)
  - Kulsoug, photographer Dick Wilson (0292-0294), 1946 July 1 (Box 1)
  - Liana Koo, photographer Dick Wilson (0295-0297), 1946 June 29 (Box 1)
  - Lai-Po, photographer Dick Wilson (0298-0301), 1946 July 8 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai Kwangwen, photographer Warren Lee (0302-0305), 1946 August 3 (Box 1)
  - Shenyang (Mukden), photographer Larry Gahn (0306-0309), 1946 July 25 (Box 1)
  - Fushon, photographer Larry Gahn (0310-0313, 0312 is missing), 1946 July 24 (Box 1)
  - Shenyang (Mukden), photographer Larry Gahn (0314-0322), 1946 July 23 (Box 1)
  - Shenyang (Mukden), photographer Larry Gahn (0323-0330), 1946 July 22 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0331), 1946 June (Box 1)
  - Zikawei, Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0332-0359), 1946 August 5 (Box 1)
  - CHT Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0360-0363), 1946 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Chao Ho Ching, photographer Warren Lee (0364-0373, 0365 is missing), 1946 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Kwangwen AMB, photographer Warren Lee (0374-0380), 1946 August 7 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0381-0390), 1946 August 8 (Box 1)
  - CHT Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0391-0393), 1946 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Western Yunnan, photographer S. C. Hsu (0394-0414), undated (Box 1)
  - Point Island, photographer Warren Lee (0415-0417), 1946 August 13 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai Wharf, photographer Larry Gahn (0418-0420, 0419 is missing), 1946 August 14 (Box 1)
  - Kao Chaio, photographer Warren Lee (0421-0428), 1946 August 23 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0429-0433), 1946 August 22 (Box 1)
  - Tanan, Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0434-0438), 1946 August 28 (Box 1)
  - Keeling, Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0439-0442), 1946 August 22 (Box 1)
  - Taipa, Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0443-0453), 1946 August 23 (Box 1)
  - Kao-hsiung (Takao), Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0454-0467), 1946 August 28 (Box 1)
  - Kao-hsiung (Takao), Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0468-0469), 1946 August 30 (Box 1)
  - Board LST Wan Hung, photographer Charles Leong (0470-0483, 0482 is missing), 1946 August 16 (Box 1)
  - South of Taipa, Taiwan, photographer Charles Leong (0484-0492), 1946 August 24 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0493-0504), 1946 September 7 (Box 1)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0505-0509), 1946 September 12 (Box 1)
  - Wuhan (Hankow), photographer Dick Wilson (0510-0515), 1946 August 28 (Box 1)
  - Wuhan (Hankow), photographer Dick Wilson (0516-0518), 1946 August 24 (Box 1)
  - Wuhan (Hankow), photographer Dick Wilson (0519-0521), 1946 August 25 (Box 1)
  - Wuhan (Hankow), photographer Dick Wilson (0522-0524), 1946 August 26 (Box 1)
  - Wuhan (Hankow), photographer Dick Wilson (0525-0526), 1946 August 27 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0527-0532), 1946 September 21 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0533-0537), 1946 September 22 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0538-0539), 1946 September 21 (Box 1)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Warren Lee (0540), 1946 September 23 (Box 2)
  - CEW Shop, photographer Warren Lee (0541), 1946 September 23 (Box 2)
  - Point Island "Brethren," photographer Larry Gahn (0542-0545), 1946 September 25 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai "International Group," photographer Larry Gahn (0546), 1946 September 27 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0547-0554), 1946 October 5 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0555-0556), 1946 October 6 (Box 2)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Larry Gahn (0557-0565), 1946 October 12 (Box 2)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Larry Gahn (0566-0582), 1946 October 14 (Box 2)
  - Point Island, photographer Larry Gahn (0583-0591, 0584 and 0588 are missing), 1946 October 8 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0592-0593), 1946 October (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0594-0602), 1946 October 8 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified, photographer Warren Lee (0603-0607), undated (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0608-0610), 1946 October 21 (Box 2)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), unidentified photographer (0611-0620), 1946 October (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0621-0623), 1946 October 25 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0624-0625), 1946 October 28 (Box 2)
  - CEW Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0626-0636), 1946 October 27 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0637-0649), 1946 October 29 (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Larry Gahn (0650-0651), 1946 November 2 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0652-0662), 1946 November 7 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (0663-0664), 1946 November 8 (Box 2)
  - Kisuson Docks, photographer Larry Gahn (0665-0667), 1946 November 8 (Box 2)
  - Wucheng, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0668-0683), 1946 October 29 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0684-0687), 1946 October 24 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0688-0692), 1946 November 1 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0693-0702), 1946 November 2 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0703-0707), 1946 October 25 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0708-0713), 1946 October 31 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0714-0717), 1946 October 25 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0718-0719), 1946 November 24 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0720-0755), 1946 October 24 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0756-0761), 1946 November 1 (Box 2)
  - Wuchang, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0762), 1946 October 29 (Box 2)
  - Takou, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0763-0767), 1946 October 26 (Box 2)
  - Keliakao, Taiyuan, photographer Warren Lee (0768-0783), 1946 November 3 (Box 2)
  - Taiyuan, Shanxi (Shansi), photographer Warren Lee (0784-0785), 1946 October 28 (Box 2)
  - Keliakao, photographer Warren Lee (0786-0792), 1946 October (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0793-0796), 1946 November 13 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0797-0798), 1946 November 23 (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Warren Lee (0799-0824), 1946 September (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Warren Lee (0825-0828), 1946 October (Box 2)
  - Nanpo, photographer Warren Lee (0829-0835), 1946 November (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer C. M. Chao (0836-0838), 1946 December 3 (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, photographer C. M. Chao (0839-0841), 1946 December 5 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai Wharf, photographer C. M. Chao (0842-0844), 1946 December 6 (Box 2)
  - Fuzhou (Foochow), photographer Larry Gahn (0845-0866, 0849 is missing), 1946 November 18 (Box 2)
  - Xiamen-Fuzhou (Amoy-Foochow), photographer Larry Gahn (0867-0888, 0870 and 0881 are missing), 1946 November 19 (Box 2)
  - Fuzhou (Foochow), photographer Larry Gahn (0889-0900), 1946 November 20 (Box 2)
  - Xiamen (Amoy), photographer Larry Gahn (0901-0912), 1946 November 23 (Box 2)
  - Xiamen (Amoy), photographer Larry Gahn (0913-0922), 1946 November 24 (Box 2)
  - Fuzhou (Foochow), photographer Larry Gahn (0923), 1946 November 24 (Box 2)
  - Xiamen (Amoy), photographer Larry Gahn (0924-0952, 0945 and 0947-0948 are missing), 1946 November 26 (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0953-0976), 1946 December 21 (Box 2)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Warren Lee (0977-0981), 1946 December 23 (Box 2)
  - Yangtzepoo, photographer Warren Lee (0982), 1946 December 22 (Box 2)
  - Airfield Longhua (Lunghwa), photographer Warren Lee (0982A), 1946 August (Box 2)
  - Yangtzepoo, photographer Warren Lee (0983), 1946 December 22 (Box 2)
  - Longhua (Lunghwa) Airfield, photographer Warren Lee (0983A), 1946 September (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0984), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (0984A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0985), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (0985A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0986), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (0986A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0987), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (0987A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0988), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Hong Kong, photographer Larry Gahn (0988A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0989), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Hong Kong, photographer Larry Gahn (0989A), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (0990-0991), 1946 December 26 (Box 2)
  - Hong Kong, photographer Larry Gahn (0991A, 0992-1000), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Missing (1001) (Box 2)
  - Kowloon-Hong Kong, photographer Larry Gahn (1002-1020), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (1021-1025), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (1026-1040), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Sluice Gate, Guangdong (Kwangtung), photographer Larry Gahn (1041-1050), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (1051-1053), 1946 December (Box 2)
  - Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (1054-1064), 1946 December (Box 3)
  - Shamian (Shameen), Guangzhou (Canton), photographer Larry Gahn (1065-1068), 1946 December (Box 3)
  - West River, Guangdong (Kwangtung), photographer Larry Gahn (1069-1082, 1077 is missing), 1946 December (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1083-1089), 1947 January 4 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (1090-1097), 1947 January 6 (Box 3)
  - Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), photographer Larry Gahn (1098-1108, 1102 is missing), 1947 January 2 (Box 3)
  - Point Island, photographer Larry Gahn (1109-1132), 1947 January 8 (Box 3)
  - Astor House, photographer Larry Gahn (1133-1142), 1947 January 13 (Box 3)
  - CHT Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (1143-1147), 1947 January 15 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1148-1153), 1947 January 21 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1154-1168), 1947 January 25 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1169-1171), 1947 January 29 (Box 3)
  - Jiangwan (Kiangwan), photographer Warren Lee (1172-1175), 1947 January 28 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1176-1181), 1947 February 2 (Box 3)
  - Jiangwan (Kiangwan), photographer Warren Lee (1182-1183), 1947 February 4 (Box 3)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Larry Gahn (1184-1187), 1947 February 11 (Box 3)
  - Longhua (Lunghwa) Airfield, photographer Larry Gahn (1188-1194), 1947 February 8 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer Warren Lee (1195-1197), 1947 February 20 (Box 3)
  - Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Larry Gahn (1198-1211), 1947 February 11 (Box 3)
  - Qingdao (Tsingtao), photographer Larry Gahn (1212-1229, 1227 is missing), 1947 February 14 (Box 3)
  - Yangtze near Nanjing (Nanking), photographer Larry Gahn (1230-1234), 1947 February 12 (Box 3)
  - Qingdao (Tsingtao) CHT, photographer Larry Gahn (1235-1241), 1947 February 14 (Box 3)
  - Jiangwan (Kiangwan), photographer C. M. Chao (1242-1248), 1947 February 20 (Box 3)
  - Qingdao (Tsingtao), photographer Larry Gahn (1249-1252, 1250 is missing), 1947 February 14 (Box 3)
  - Point Island, photographer C. M. Chao (1253-1258), 1947 March 1 (Box 3)
  - Point Island, photographer C. M. Chao (1259-1270), 1947 March 6 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer C. M. Chao (1271-1273), 1947 March 6 (Box 3)
  - Huangpu (Whangpoo), Shanghai, photographer Larry Gahn (1274-1281), 1946 March 14 (Box 3)
  - Point Island, photographer Larry Gahn (1282-1292), 1947 March 18 (Box 3)
  - Astor House, photographer Larry Gahn (1293-1297), 1947 March 24 (Box 3)
  - Point Island, photographer Warren Lee (1298-1320), 1947 March 28 (Box 3)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Larry Gahn (1321-1322), 1947 January (Box 3)
  - New Asia Hotel, photographer Larry Gahn (1323-1333), 1947 March 28 (Box 3)
  - Shanghai, photographer C. M. Chao (1334-1341), 1947 April 8 (Box 3)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Warren Lee (1342-1352), 1947 April 6 (Box 3)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Warren Lee (1353-1359), 1947 April 7 (Box 3)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Warren Lee (1360-1376), 1947 April 8 (Box 3)
  - Hangzhou (Hangchow), photographer Warren Lee (1377-1390), 1947 April 9 (Box 3)
  - CNRRA office, photographer Warren Lee (1391-1393), 1947 April 21 (Box 3)
  - Henan (Honan), photographer Dick Wilson (1394-1398), 1947 April 13 (Box 3)
  - Henan (Honan), photographer Dick Wilson (1394-1398), 1947 April 13 (Box 3)
  - Huayuankuo, Henan (Honan), photographer Dick Wilson (1399-1403), 1947 April 16 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), Henan (Honan), photographer Dick Wilson (1404-1406), 1947 April 16 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), Henan (Honan), photographer Dick Wilson (1407-1409), 1947 April 15 (Box 3)
  - Fukou (Fukow), photographer Dick Wilson (1410-1414), 1947 April 14 (Box 3)
  - Anhui (Anhwei), Peng-Pu, photographer Dick Wilson (1415-1417), 1947 April 18 (Box 3)
  - Unidentified (1418-1419) (Box 3)
  - Near Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1420-1421), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Huayuankuo, Henan (Honan), photographer Larry Gahn (1422), 1947 April 14 (Box 3)
  - Near Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1423), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1424), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Huayuankuo, photographer Larry Gahn (1425-1430), 1947 April 14 (Box 3)
  - Fukou (Fukow), Henan (Honan), photographer Larry Gahn (1431-1448, 1434, 1439, and 1443 are missing), 1947 April 15 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1449-1460), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Kaifeng, photographer Larry Gahn (1461-1464), 1947 April 15 (Box 3)
  - Fukou (Fukow), Henan (Honan), photographer Larry Gahn (1465-1467), 1947 April 15 (Box 3)
  - Kaifeng, photographer Larry Gahn (1468-1469), 1947 April 16 (Box 3)
  - Henan (Honan), photographer Larry Gahn (1470-1471), 1947 April 17 (Box 3)
  - Kaifeng, photographer Larry Gahn (1472), 1947 April 16 (Box 3)
  - Fukou (Fukow), photographer Larry Gahn (1473), 1947 April 15 (Box 3)
  - Henan (Honan), photographer Larry Gahn (1474), 1947 April 17 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1475-1476), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Anhui (Anhwei), near Peng-Pu; photographer Larry Gahn (1477-1481), 1947 April 18 (Box 3)
  - Zhengzhou (Chengchow), photographer Larry Gahn (1482-1485), 1947 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Huayuankuo, photographer Larry Gahn (1486-1492), 1947 April 14 (Box 3)